so there's five home insurance discounts
that you're likely not aware of these
are some of the unique ones and pieces
that a lot of people don't know exist
now a lot has changed in the last
probably two years or so where the
pandemic has changed a lot the price of
wood has made the cost of homes to go up
and a lot of the different scenarios
with hurricanes and different events in
texas where we've had a lot of damage in
other states where it just wasn't
typical well because of that there's
been a lot of things that insurance
companies have looked at and some of the
things that they've always gone for and
people don't realize is the first piece
your marital status plays a factor
whether you're married or not in some
states don't matter but more so
in most states it does affect the rate
that's why they're constantly asking are
you married single or widowed divorced
or separated depending on what you
choose there the rate could change in
the state that you're in the married
couples tend to have less accidents they
also from a financial standpoint tend to
want to bundle their home and their auto
insurance and are likely open for life
insurance so there's a lot more products
that they can go after and there's a
reason and a good reason that they're
going to want to go after more discounts
to pull that person in to see if there's
other products as well as the risk is
generally lower now that one's gonna net
you about a five percent discount on
average that's pretty common it's three
to five percent for having the marital
discount the second one is having a
fortified home now this isn't going to
be in every state that you're in but
anywhere near a coastline like alabama
or texas or florida you guys have a lot
of weather damage and insurance
companies will give you a discount for
fortifying and saving your home from
natural disasters i believe in florida
there's tie downs that you can put over
your roof that will actually protect
your roof from blowing off in the event
of a hurricane there's a bunch of
different things that they're going to
apply for this discount i'm going to
list a few from this article i'm reading
on yahoo finance where they have
hurricane shutters in michigan we have
kind of fake shutters but they don't
shut these actually have to function and
close off the actual home the roof has
hurricane straps like we just mentioned
in florida that's a very common thing
hill resistant roofs that's actually a
discount in a lot of states even in
michigan that's a question that they ask
because those roofs not only are hill
resistant but they last longer they're
typically your 50 plus your roof and
they know that there's not likely going
to be any damage if at all in the next
20 plus years having a house generator
also helps whether it's a backup that
you have to hook up is kind of a
discount but if you have a
self-sustained one that instantly kicks
in when there's an event where the power
goes out a lot of times it's on a
farmland uh that's where you see them
the most and they're in the little wood
boxes if you've ever seen lit looks like
a dog house there's usually a generator
in there and it's just a backup in case
the power goes out a fire sprinkler
system in the house fairly rare but that
used to be a common question especially
in states like california it seemed like
they had those more often than not it
tends to fall into the renter's category
because most renting dwellings will have
that but in some homes they also add
that as well and on top of it different
things like lightning protection
smart smoke alarms so these are becoming
the more common and smart sensors so if
you have a water detection service or
device that shuts your water off if it
notice that there's a leak insurance
companies have gone so far to actually
sell this at a discounted price so that
they can protect themselves as well as
you for the homeowner that might want to
have that extra level of protection now
these smoke alarms in these devices and
fire alarms they call them smart they
used to be called internal or they used
to be called central devices and what
essentially that does is it notifies you
either via an app or and it will notify
the police or fire department if there's
an occurrence you never know you come
home and the fire department's just
sitting there with the lights flashing
and it tells you that your device went
off kind of a nice thing to have it's
unfortunate if it glitches because now
you have to foot the bill for the fire
department to show up the third one is
going to be your mortgage if you are a
mortgage-free homeowner you're going to
get a discount for that so having that
mortgage go away
shows that the insurance that you're
financially responsible and we're going
to talk a little bit more about that at
the end because the fifth one is going
to go into depth a little bit more on
that number four is an age piece and
partially a financial piece where if
you're retired or retiree you're going
to get a large discount on that that's
actually one of the best discounts that
i find it's typically not necessarily
tied specifically to retirees although
some companies do if you're 50 or older
that's the age range that's perfect
also they have what's called a retiree
discount so typically when you're 50 or
older the companies will allow you to
apply the retiree discount whether
you're retired or not now it used to be
that that was really heavily checked and
that was a big piece but a lot of these
companies just haven't changed the names
of them and they have allowed those to
go through other companies you've got to
be careful because we don't want to
cheat the system and say you're retired
when you're not so if you don't have
approval from the company i don't
recommend just throwing that discount
out there where you're getting the wrong
risk for the wrong person essentially
i've seen the retiree discount go above
in this article it says 10 percent i
know it's a bigger discount on the home
more than it is on the auto so if you're
a cpa or you're an engineer or you're
some sort of uh occupational or more
union member or some sort of affiliate
typically on the auto you're going to
get a better discount there and then on
the home you're going to get the best
discount that i've seen is being a
retiree in the fifth but not the final
because there's a handful more that you
guys want to learn i'll talk about them
here in just a second is going to be
your credit score and this is what we
call an insurance score i actually just
made a video that goes into depth i will
link it here that you can watch it after
this video because it plays a large
factor on your insurance premium
surprisingly enough i put a poll out
there not a lot of people knew that
insurance score or credit scores played
a factor and it actually plays one of
the biggest factors just like we talked
about earlier where we were talking
about how the financial risk being
retired paying off your home being
married having extra income buying other
products
it's a business and they're finding the
best fits for clients
well if you have a good credit score
you're likely financially responsible
and you're not likely to file claims and
have those additional pieces go against
you well in this case what we're talking
about is the pieces that make up an
insurance court and that's what that
video is going to talk about is 30 is
because of your credit and 40 is because
the longevity of your credit and all of
that plays a factor along with your clue
report which is more tickets accidents
things like that and those make up what
we call an insurance score and that
insurance score does play a large factor
can be hundreds of dollars different
depending on what ranking that they give
you in that scoring now that's not the
end all be all because i actually have a
video that goes into depth on the
additional 15 discounts that you should
have on your car insurance and home
insurance so i'm going to go ahead and
link that video here for you guys to
watch so go ahead and check that video
out there it's the top 15 discounts that
you get insurance if you haven't
reviewed the main home 101 i'm going to
link this video here as well i'm mark
with think insurance
i'll see in the next one